Guide to the Morris Schappes Papers TAM.179
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Jewish Currents Files, 1958-2004
  - Subseries IIC: Administrative Files
    - Israel / Salute to Israel Parade, 1994, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Articles: Drafts, Proofs - April 2001 Issue (I) (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Articles: Drafts, Proofs - April 2001 Issue (II) (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Articles: Drafts, Proofs - April 2001 Issue (III) (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Articles: Drafts, Proofs - Various, 2000, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Currents: "The Editor's Diary" - Drafts, Notes and Related Materials, Sep 1999-Oct 1999 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents: "The Editor's Diary" - Drafts, Notes and Related Materials, Nov 1999-Dec 1999 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents: "The Editor's Diary" - Drafts, Notes and Related Materials, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Currents: "The Editor's Diary" - Drafts, Notes and Related Materials, Jan 2000-Mar 2000 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Jewish Currents: "The Editor's Diary" - Drafts, Notes and Related Materials, Apr 2000-Jul 2000 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Jewish Currents Events, 1958-1989 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1967 (21st Anniversary) Dinner Journal (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1972 Dinner - Schappes' 65th Birthday Journal (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1977 Dinner (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1986 Journal (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1987 Concert - "A Musical Portrait of Emma Goldman (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1987 Dinner - Schappes' 80th Birthday (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1988 Dinner, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1989 Concert (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1989 Dinner, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1989 Dinner - Journal, 1987-1989 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1990 Luncheon - Journal (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1991 Concert - "Songs of Jews, Peace and Women" (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1991 Luncheon (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1992 Concert - "Two Dances on Jewish Themes" (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1992 Luncheon - Schappes' 85th Birthday (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1993 Luncheon (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1995 Luncheon (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1997 Luncheon - Schappes' 90th Birthday (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1997 Luncheon - Schappes' 90th Birthday (Joseph Murphy Speech) (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1997 Luncheon - Schappes' 90th Birthday - Journal (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1998 Concert, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 1999 Luncheon - Journal (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2000 Luncheon (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2000 Luncheon - Journal Prep (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2001 Luncheon (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2001 Luncheon - Journal (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2002 Luncheon (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2002 Luncheon - Journal (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Jewish Currents Events: 2003-2005 Luncheons (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Jewish Currents Events: Socialist Scholars Conference 1986 - Black-Jewish Relations Workshop (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Jewish Currents Events: Socialist Scholars Conference 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Jewish Currents: History, 1956-1957, 1990, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Jewish Women Now Pamphlet, 1984-1990 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Music Review Material, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Music Review Material, 1993-1997 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Permissions, 1986-1991 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Permissions, 1992-2000 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Prizes: Announcements and Entries, 1985-1994 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Reader Questionnaire, 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Reader Questionnaire, 1986-1987, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Reader Questionnaire on Columns, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Typographical Layout for Jewish Currents (Silas Snider), 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Series III: WBAI Broadcasts, 1966-1994
  In September of 1966, Morris Schappes began hosting a weekly "Commentary on Jewish Affairs" at FM radio station WBAI, New York. The station advertised the program as "a secular Jewish point of view on contemporary Jewish development in relation to general American issues and in relation to Jewish life and cultural expression in literature and the arts." This series contains broadcast materials from September 6, 1966 through May 30, 1967. Topics vary and include such titles as "Johnson, the Jews and Vietnam," "East Side, East Side, A Museum View," "Black Power and the Jews" and "Morton Sobell on our Conscience". There are transcripts of the broadcasts along with newspaper clippings, magazine articles, correspondence and notes associated with Schappes' research and preparation. The series also contains a small amount of material related to other WBAI programs hosted by Jewish Currents in 1981 and 1994.
  Broadcasts are arranged in chronological order.
  - WBAI, 1966-1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - WBAI: "Johnson, the Jews and Vietnam", Sep 6, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - WBAI: "Johnson Openly Threatens the Jews", Sep 13, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - WBAI: "Rosh Hashanah and Jewish Identity", Sep 20, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - WBAI: "Chancellor Erhard, Go Home...", Sep 27, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - WBAI: "Jews Resent Johnson's Threats" (I), Oct 4, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - WBAI: "Jews Resent Johnson's Threats" (II), Oct 4, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - WBAI: "Peter Weiss's 'The Investigation'" (I), Oct 11, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - WBAI: "Peter Weiss's 'The Investigation'" (II), Oct 11, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - WBAI: "East Side, East Side, A Museum View", Oct 18, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - WBAI: "Israel Confronts Syria in the United Nations" (I), Oct 25, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - WBAI: "Israel Confronts Syria in the United Nations" (II), Oct 25, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - WBAI: "Two More Jewish Nobel Prizes in Literature" - Shmuel Yosef Agnon and Nelly L. Sach (I), Nov 1, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - WBAI: "Two More Jewish Nobel Prizes in Literature" - Shmuel Yosef Agnon and Nelly L. Sach (II), Nov 1, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - WBAI: "Security Council Evades Syrian-Israel Crisis", Nov 8, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - WBAI: "Black Power and the Jews", Nov 15, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - WBAI: "The Anti-Semitic Blood Libel in Fact and Fiction" (I), Nov 22, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - WBAI: "The Anti-Semitic Blood Libel in Fact and Fiction" (II), Nov 22, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - WBAI: "The UN Censured Israel - What Now?", Nov 29, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - WBAI: The Harlem Six, [1966,1967] (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - WBAI: "The Symptom of Wayne Township, U.S.A." (I), Mar 7, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - WBAI: "The Symptom of Wayne Township, U.S.A." (II), Mar 7, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - WBAI: "Powell and Jewish Public Opinion" (Adam Clayton Powell, James H. Meredith), Mar 14, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - WBAI: "The CIA and Jewish Affairs in the Middle East", Mar 28, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - WBAI: "The New York Constitutional Convention: The Church-State Issue" (I), Apr 4, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - WBAI: "The New York Constitutional Convention: The Church-State Issue" (II), Apr 4, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - WBAI: "Morton Sobell on Our Conscience", Apr 11, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - WBAI: "The Warsaw Ghetto and Other Uprisings", Apr 18, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - WBAI: "Passover and Jewish Identity", Apr 25, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - WBAI: "James Baldwin and Anti-Semitism", May 9, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - WBAI: "Israel on her 19th Birthday", May 16, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - WBAI: "A New Controversy about Treblinka", May 23, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - WBAI: "The Middle East: A Breathing Spell -- or Explosion", May 30, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - WBAI Programs, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - WBAI Programs, 1981, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1911-2004
  The largest by far, this series provides an in-depth look at Morris Schappes' wide-ranging interests. It is composed of material he collected either as background for his many books, articles, reviews, editorials, letters to the editor, radio broadcasts and classroom teaching, or simply because the items were of interest to him. His annotations are found throughout the many newspaper clippings, articles, event programs, exhibit catalogs, reviews, obituaries and publications in the series.
  Emma Lazarus was of particular interest to Schappes. Lazarus-related material includes manuscript drafts, typescript and galleys for his writings along with related notes, clippings, transcriptions of her letters, reviews, press releases, scripts, sheet music and a good amount of correspondence. Black-Jewish relations is another well-represented topic, as is antisemitism, particularly as depicted in Shakespeare's The Merchant of Venice and Dickens' Oliver Twist. Other topics of interest include academic freedom, immigration, Communism, secularism, the Red Scare, reproductive rights and Israel. Among the many historical, political and literary figures in whom Schappes took an interest are Saul Bellow, Philip Roth, Ilya Ehrenberg, Roy Cohn, Mario Cuomo, Ernestine Louise Rose, the Foner family (Eric, Henry, Jack, Moe and Philip), Sherwin Wine, Thomas Jefferson and Sally Hemmings, Pete Seeger, and Julius and Ethel Rosenberg. Organizations such as the Jewish People's Franternal Order and such topics as Holocaust history, the Bicentennial of the American Revolution and the Bakke Case are also represented.
  A significant portion of the series is devoted to Schappes' research, much of it identified with either A Documentary History of the Jews in the United States, 1654-1877 or The Jews in the United States: A Pictorial History, 1954 to the Present. There is also general research material on Jewish history, Jewish identity and culture, and Jewish labor history.
  A number of book, film and theater reviews are included, along with pamphlets, newsletters, reports and other publications. Of the newspaper clippings and journal articles scattered throughout the series, many are written in Yiddish and a few are in French or Spanish.
  - Academic Freedom, 1937, 1948-1951, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Ackley, John Kenneth, 1941-1945, 1973-1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Actors' Union" (Hebrew Actors Union), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Albright, Madeleine K., 1997 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - AL-FAJR Jerusalem Palestinian Weekly, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Allen, Charles R., 1986-1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers, 1944-1949 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers, 1950-1954 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers, 1955-1991 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - "America, Franklin D. Roosevelt and the Holocaust": Public Lecture by William J. Vanden Heuvel, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - American Committee on Africa: Divestment of Funds from Companies in South Africa, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - American History: Communist Perspective, 1946-1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - American Indians, 1968-1978 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1943-1957 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1958-1967, 1979, 1984, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - American Revolution and the Colonial Era, 1959-1991 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Americans for Peace Now, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Americans for Progressive Israel--Hashomer Hatzair, Los Angeles Chapter, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Anarchists, 1945-1985, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Andrew Goodman Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1973, 1993, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1923, 2004, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Anti-Semitism: AHA Papers on Black Anti-Semitism, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Anti-Semitism: Benjamin Franklin, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Anti-Semitism: General George S. Brown, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Anti-Semitism: Soviet, 1964-1982 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Anti-Semitism: Soviet, Leningrad Trials, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Anti-war Flyers, 1940-1941 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1946-1947, 1970, 1989, undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Armenians, 1915, 1942, 1969, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Armenians, 1915, 1986-1990 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Armenians, 1915, 1990-1994 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Arnoni Award, 1987-1996 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Art: Various Clippings, 1962-1996 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Auschwitz: Plea to Bomb, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Australian Jewish Democratic Society, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Bakers, Butchers, Food, 1949-1957, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Bakke Case (Racial Bias in College Admissions), Feb 1977-Sep 1977 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Bakke Case (Racial Bias in College Admissions), Oct 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Baldwin, James (Julius Lester and Anti-Semitism), 1967, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Barondess, Joseph, 1911-1957, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1964-1969 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1970-1974 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1980-1999 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Berger, David, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Bibliographies, Indices and End Notes: Various, [1953], 1980, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Bicentennial (American Revolution) Celebration: Background, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Bicentennial (American Revolution) Celebration: Background, 1971-1976 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - "Big Business", 1951-1957 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Black History / Issues, 1943-1999, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Black-Jewish Relations, 1931, 1956, 1971-1998, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Black-Jewish Relations, 1973-1999 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: Amsterdam News, 1986, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: "'A Bunch of Jews Defending Them Damned Niggers!': Radical Jews in the ILD's Scottsboro Campaign," J. R. Uhlmann, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: "Historical Impressions of Black-Jewish Relations Prior to WWII...", 1978 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: Jews, Blacks and Slavery (Jewish Life and Jewish Currents Reprints), 1948-1954, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: "Jews and Zionism: The Views of Marcus Garvey," William Seraile, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Black-Jewish Relations ("Negroes and Jews"): Research Notes, Articles and Related Material, 1945-1964 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: Slavery (Reprints from Jewish Life), 1948-1954 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: "What Do We Know about Black Anti-Semitism?" Jennifer L. Golub, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Black Radical Congress, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: "The Search for Roots: The Jewish and African Experiences" - World Jewish Congress Conference Descriptive Materials, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Blacks and Jews: "The Gold-Dust Twins of Marginal Humor," Joseph Dorinson, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Bloch, Joshua, 1950-1961, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Bondi, August, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Book Reviews: A-J (Book Authors), 1939, 1946, 1974-2000 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Book Reviews: K-Z, 1948, 1962-1999 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Bovshover, Joseph, 1971-1985 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Boxerman, Nahoma and Abe, 1986-1991 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Braunlich, Arthur, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Brickner, Balfour, 1981, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Brooklyn Neighborhoods, 1975-1992 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Buchanan, Patrick J., 1990 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Bush, Larry, 1980-1989 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Bush, Larry, 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Bush, Larry, 1993-1997 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Bush, Larry, 2001-2002, undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Butz, Earl, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Cacchione, Peter V., 1947, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Camp Kinderland, 1993-2002 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Campus Issues (Various Colleges and Universities), 1989-1993 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Caribbean, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Census Statistics (Various): New York State (1647-1764), undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1976-1978, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1983-1993 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Christopher Columbus Quincentenary, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Cigar Makers, 1948-1957, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Citron, Alice, 1941-1988 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - City College of New York (CCNY), 1965, 1979-1991 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - CCNY: "The City College of New York: Struggles and Successes, 1920-1982" (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - CCNY: Knickerbocker Case (Anti-Semitism), 1938, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - CCNY: Open Admission, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - CCNY: Student Activism, 1969, 1989, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - CCNY: Student Publications, 1931-1938 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - CCNY: Student Survey (CUNY), 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - CCNY: Tragedy at Celebrity Basketball Game (12/28/1991), 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - City University of New York (CUNY), 1982-1984 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights Struggle: Research, 1948-1949, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Clinton-Lewinsky Relationship: Jewish Press Reaction, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics, 1944-1976 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics, 1977-2000, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish, 1940s (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish (I), 1950s (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish (II), 1950s (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Clippings and Articles: Various Topics - Yiddish, 1980s, undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Collection Ideas (Fundraising), 1959-1965, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Committee for Equality in Education, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Communism: China, 1976-1987 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Communism: Europe, 1947, 1962-1978 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Communism: Europe, 1979-1990 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Communism: USA, 1981-1985 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Communism: USSR, 1981-1986 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Communist Party: Jews in the USSR, 1957-1958, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Communist Party: New York State Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Conference on Jewish Culture in English: Schappes' Report and Article along with Related Material, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Cooperatives, 1927, undated (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Cruse, Harold, 1967-1991 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Cuba (includes letter to Philip Foner re: St.Louis attempt to disembark in Cuba - 1939), 1962, 1979-1981 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Cuomo, Mario, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Cuomo, Mario, 1987-1990 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Cuomo, Mario: Photographs, 1986, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Czechoslovakia (Post-War), 1948 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Leon, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Lionel, 1984-1992 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Death Threats and Extremist Groups, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Deir Yassin, 1969, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Democratic Socialists of America, 1986-1991 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Dershowitz, Alan, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - DeVore, Jesse L., Jr.: Material re: "Faith Journey", 1994 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Dimow, Joe, 1979-1990 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Doctorow, E. L., 1983-1987 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews in the United States: 1654-1875: Background/Research (I), 1947-1951, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Background/Research (II), 1947-1951, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Background/Research (III), 1947-1951, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Clippings, 1950-1955 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Correspondence, 1946-1953, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Correspondence with Communist Party Officials Gil Green and Earl Browder, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Correspondence with Bertram Korn (Includes Discussion of Korean War), 1950 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Correspondence Related to Publication, 1945-1957, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Notes, 1945-1955, undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Preface by Dr. Joshua Bloch, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Publicity, 1947-1997, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Reviews, 1950-1952, undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Royalty Statements and Other Financial Materials, 1950-1963 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Salomon, Haym - Correspondence, Clippings, 1944-1959 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Salomon, Haym - Photostats, Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - A Documentary History of the Jews...: Salomon, Haym - Research Notes, undated (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Domoff, Judith C.: "A Trip to the Soviet Union July 24-Aug 16, 1983", 1983, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Dora Teitelboim Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Dorinson, Joseph, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Dube, Ernest F. (Tenure Case), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Edelman, Joseph, 1984-1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Education: Equal Opportunity, 1974-1999 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya, 1936-1959 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya, 1961-1981, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya (Clippings in Yiddish), 1943-1959 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya (Clippings in Yiddish), 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya (Clippings in Yiddish), 1963-1984 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya: Writings, 1936-1961, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Eisenberger, Sidney, [1976], 1979 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Elias, Joe (Ladino/Sephardic Music), 1985-1995, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - "Elegy for Stanley Gorski" by Emmanuel Fried, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Ethnicity / Diversity (I), 1975-1984 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Ethnicity / Diversity (II), 1975-1984 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - "Ethnicity in Suburbia: The Long Island Experience" (with Schappes' Notes), 1980 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Ewen, Frederic (The Frederic Ewen Center for Academic Freedom - Brooklyn College), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Fast, Howard: "An Epitaph for Sidney", 1947 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Fast, Howard: "The Price of Liberty", 1950 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1966-1977 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Feingold, Henry, 1989, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Fellman, Gordon, 1987-1995 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Film and Theater, 1961-2002, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Fischer, Joseph, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Foner, Eric, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Foner, Henry, 1992-2002 (Box 25, Folder 27)